Inji Samir



CONTACT



+971 551656205



Inji.samir@icloud.com



Egyptian



www.linkedin.com/in/inji-samir-3643552a/



Emirates Hills, Dubai- UAE

LANGUAGES

English, Arabic, French

CORE COMPETENCIES

- -Marketing communication strategies
- -Corporate reputation building
- -Crisis management
- -Internal & external communications
- -Digital marketing
- -Corporate, product & retail branding
- Strategic partnerships
- -Corporate social responsibility programs -B2B & B2C
- Public Relations/Media & press
- -Government relations
- -Copy writing & content development
- -Events Management
- -Advertising & promotional campaigns
- -Project management
- -Research
- -Budgets

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Marketing communications professional with a vast experience in a fast-paced growing environment working across different industries ranging from electronics and home appliances to entertainment, building materials, consulting and media. Strong passion and persistence in delivering complex projects from concept design to implementation to build favorable and memorable brands. Ability to build and develop high performing teams while engaging the relevant stakeholders from executives to operational level.

SUMMARY ACHIEVEMENTS

- Recognized by the Egyptian Minister of Education for Vocational Training and the Holcim Group for Lafarge educational CSR program
- Successfully implemented 2 industry educational events that led to a multimillion dollars contract signing
- Implemented customized media campaigns thus increasing OSN brand awareness from 43 to 85% in 4 years

EXPERIENCE

HEAD OF COMMUNICATIONS

Lafarge, member of Holcim

Cairo, Egypt

 Managed the company's image and reputation through the development and implementation of a robust internal and external communication strategy targeting the different stakeholders

2017 - 2019

- Secured positive PR coverage in premium media outlets through an effective PR strategy and enhanced media relations
- Weathered multiple media crisis thus turning negative coverage to positive
- Partnered with the relevant government stakeholders and business partners to lobby for industry and company related issues and challenges
- Managed corporate and industry events and forums to support the company's positioning as an industry leader
- Coordinated with local and international media to maximize exposure opportunities
- Initiated internal communication activities and programs to enhance the relationship between top management and the employees while ensuring smooth dissemination of information from top to bottom and vice versa
- Handled the company's social media outlets
- Supported the group in regional and global projects development and implementation including the 6th International LafargeHolcim foundation Forum for Sustainable Construction with the attendance of 350 globally renowned architects
- Managed the design and production of all collaterals and video production materials
- Improved the comms' team performance through ongoing coaching and identification of training needs to ensure continuous development and growth

Personal Information

Date of Birth: November 1st, 1975 Place of birth: Cairo, Egypt Nationality: Egyptian

Marital status: Married with 2 kids Residency: on husband's visa

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

MARKETING MANAGER

OSN 2012 -2017

Cairo, Egypt

- Marketing communication strategy development while ensuring alignment with the group vision and business objectives
- Identification of potential customers needs and buying lifecycle through research and market insights to develop programs that support sales growth and buying decision process
- Supervision of all ATL and BTL materials production and media buys while implementing a SMART spend strategy to increase reach and reduce cost
- Development of retail programs and initiatives for B2B sales channel to reach new target segments
- Collaboration with the sales team (direct/ dealers / commercial) to provide relevant display tools and sales collaterals
- Initiation of partnership deals with the relevant business partners such as Vodaphone and Etisalat to create positive brand association and increase reach
- Assessment of relevant sponsorship opportunities and exhibitions management
- Organization of new channels and TV shows launches
- Implementation of the built and revamp of showrooms and sales stands to reflect the new corporate image
- Creation of mega customer engagement road shows with third party channels (Disney/WWE...etc) to reach out to new target segments
- Vendors sourcing and management

CONSULTING MANAGER

CID Consulting

2007 -2012

Cairo, Egypt

- Led the marketing communication consultancy services provided to selected CID clients
- Developed the crisis communication strategy for CID clients
- Media relations development with different reporters in key publications
- Events organization and management on behalf of clients
- Proposals drafting and pitch preparation
- New business leads generation out of existing and new customers
- Recruitment and management of 3rd party suppliers
- Budget allocation and implementation for the assigned projects
- Recruitment and management of a team of consultants while ensuring proper coaching
- Managed the production of the different company's communication materials

ASSISTANT MARKETING MANAGER

Fresh electric for Home Appliances.
Cairo, Egypt

2005 -2017

SENIOR MARKETING EXECUTIVE & PR SPECIALIST

LG 2001 -2005

Cairo, Egypt

EDUCATION

BACHELOR DEGREE IN ARTS

MAJOR JOURNALISM & MASS COMMUNICATION
The American University in Cairo (AUC)

1999